Guide to the Sylvester Manor Archive 1649-1996 MSS.208
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Record Group IV: Horsford Family
  - Series A: Eben Norton Horsford
    - Subseries 1: Correspondence
      - Subsubseries a: Academic and Family
        - Harry, Fanny C: Waltham, MA, 1890 January 7; cuid2050 (Box 61, Folder 1)
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / Professional; American Geographical Society
        - Hart, Albert Bushnell: Cambridge, MA, 1890 February 11; cuid2051 (Box 61, Folder 2)
          Sent From: “Albert Bushnell Hart, Harvard College, Cambridge, MA”
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / History / Professional; Shepherd Historical Society
          Measurements: 7.5” x 8.5”
          Albert Bushnell Hart (July 1, 1854 – July 16, 1943) was an American educator, historian, and writer. The Papers of Albert Bushnell Hart (1874-1943) are preserved at Harvard University in Cambridge, MA.
        - Harty, John: East Providence, RI, 1890 April 6; cuid2052 (Box 61, Folder 3)
          Sent From: “Pastor John Harty, Sacred Heart Church, East Providence, RI”
          In Reference To: Business / Professional / Religion; Dedication of St. Mary
        - Harvard University: Boston, MA, 1890 April 17, 25 & 30; cuid2053 (Box 61, Folder 4)
          Sent From: “[Dean] Charles P. Lyman, F.R.C.V.S., Harvard University, School of Veterinary Medicine / Veterinary Department / Hospital Department, 50 Village Street, Boston,” [MA]
          In Reference To: Business / Professional / Science; Horses
          Measurements: 8.25” x 5.5” - 8" x 10.5"
        - Hascall, AP: Le Roy & Rochester, NY, 1836 May 16; 1841 July 24; 1843 October 26; cuid2054 (Box 61, Folder 5)
          Addressed To: “Professor Eben N. [Norton] Horsford, Esq., ℅ W. Gould, Esq., Albany / Saratoga Spa, NY,” "Moscow, Livingston County, NY"
          Sent From: “[Judge] A.P. Hascall, Le Roy / Rochester,” [NY], [Possibly Augustus Porter Hascall, Father of Melvin C. Hascall]
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / Financial / History / Professional
          Measurements: 7.75” x 12.5” - 8.5" x 12.5"
        - Hascall, HHH: Le Roy, NY, 1840 February 20; cuid2055 (Box 61, Folder 6)
          Addressed To: “Dear Cousin,” “Eben N. [Norton] Horsford, Esq., Albany, NY”
          Sent From: “H.H.H. Hascall,” [Unconfirmed Cousin of Eben Norton Horsford]
          In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Social; Illustration of Room Design / Layout
        - Hascall, Mary C: Chicago, IL, 1890 January 20; cuid2056 (Box 61, Folder 7)
          Sent From: “Cousin Mary C. Hascall, 31 - 31st Street, Chicago,” [IL], [Cousin of Eben Norton Horsford]
          In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Social; Julia Horsford, Mr. Ole Bull, Scandinavian History
        - Hascall, Melvin C: New York, NY, 1889 January 22; cuid2057 (Box 61, Folder 8)
          Addressed To: “Eben [Norton] Horsford, Cambridge,” [MA]
          Sent From: “Melvin C. Hascall, ℅ Consolidated Coupling Company, Aldrich Court, 45 Broadway / 131 East 86th Street, New York,” [NY], [Son of Judge A.P. Hascall]
          In Reference To: Business / Professional; Professor Doremus
        - Hathaway, EH: Sonora, Mexico, 1887 September 17 & 20; cuid2058 (Box 61, Folder 9)
          Addressed To: “Professor E.N. [Eben Norton] Horsford, Vice President, Rumford Chemical Works, Providence, RI”
          Sent From: “E.H. Hathaway, St. Helena Gold Mine, Las Delicias, Sonora, Mexico”
          In Reference To: Business / Financial / Legal / Professional; L.W. Mix, Esq., Legal Representative of Malter Lind & Company
        - Hawley, HS: Newark, NJ, 1872 May 23; cuid2059 (Box 61, Folder 10)
          Sent From: “H.S. Hawley, State Bank Building, Newark, NJ”
          In Reference To: Business / History / Professional; Survey of Shelter Island, Beers Comstock Cline
        - Hayes, Caroline P: Cambridge, MA, 1889 June 29; cuid2060 (Box 61, Folder 11)
          Sent From: “Caroline P. Hayes, Elmwood Avenue,” [Cambridge, MA]
        - Haynes, Lorenza: Waltham, MA, 1890 October 20; cuid2061 (Box 61, Folder 12)
          Sent From: “Reverend Miss Lorenza Haynes”
          In Reference To: Business / History / Professional; Norumbega; Watertown Dedication
        - Headley JHB: Boston, MA, 1887 August 24; cuid2062 (Box 61, Folder 13)
          Sent From: “J.H.B. Headley, Parker House, School Street, Corner of Tremont, Boston,” [MA]
          In Reference To: Business / History / Professional; Elmwood; Providence
        - Healy, Edith: Paris, France, 1887 January 14 & February 20; cuid2063 (Box 61, Folder 14)
          Sent From: “Edith Healy, 66 Rue de la Rochefoucauld,” [Paris, France], [Daughter of George Peter Alexander Healy]
          In Reference To: Art / Friendship / Personal / Social / Travel; Copies of George Peter Alexander Healy’s Abraham Lincoln Portrait; Wellesley College
          Measurements: 4.75” x 3.5”
        - Healy, George Peter Alexander: New York, NY; Paris, France, 1884 May 2 - 1885 October 31; 1888 January 4 - 1890 September 17; cuid2064 (Box 61, Folder 15)
          12 Letters with Notation & Reproductions
          Addressed To: “Professor [Eben Norton] Horsford, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge,” [MA]
          Sent From: “George P.A. [Peter Alexander] Healy, 66 Rue de la Rochefoucauld, Paris,” [France], “Park Avenue Hotel, New York,” [NY]
          In Reference To: Art / Business / Financial / Friendship / Personal / Professional / Social / Travel; Originals & Photocopies with Typed Transcription; Exhibition at the Royal Academy, The National Portrait Gallery, South Kensington Museum; Madame Henri Greville, Miss Sarah Orne Jewett; Portrait of Miss Horsford; Portrait of Dr. Wyman
          25 Pages, Bound & Unbound
          Measurements: 4.25” x 7” - 8.5” x 11”
          George Peter Alexander Healy (July 15, 1813 – June 24, 1894) was an American portrait painter. Healy archival material can be found at the Filson Historical Society in Louisville, KY and the New York Public Library in New York, NY.
        - Heliotype Printing Company: Boston, MA, 1887 February 2 - 1890 April 25; undated, circa 1880s; cuid2065 (Box 61, Folder 16)
          15 Letters, 6 Memorandums
          Sent From: “Sidney A. Kimber / Treasurer Donald Ramsay, The Heliotype Printing Company, 211 Tremont Street, Boston, MA”
          In Reference To: Business / Financial / Professional; Wellesley College Interiors & Various Print Orders
        - Henry, HO: Rome, NY, 1836 December 17; cuid2066 (Box 61, Folder 17)
          Addressed To: “E.N. [Eben Norton] Horsford, Esq., Engineer Corps, Rochester & Auburn R.R., Moscow, Livingston County, NY”
          Sent From: “H.O. Henry”
        - Henry, Joseph: Washington, D.C., 1856 January 21; 1876 January 8; cuid2067 (Box 61, Folder 18)
          Sent From: “Secretary Joseph Henry, Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C.,”
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / Food / Professional / Science; Manufacture of Starch
        - Herford, Mrs. Brooke: Cambridge, MA, 1890 October 17 & 24; cuid2068 (Box 61, Folder 19)
          1 Invitation, 1 United States Postal Card with Notation & Postage
          Addressed To: "Professor [Eben Norton] Horsford, Cambridge / Lenox, MA"
          Sent From: "Mrs. Brooke Herford, 12 Chestnut Street," [Cambridge, MA]
          In Reference To: Friendship / Personal / Social; Miss Toulmin Smith
          Measurements: 5.25" x 3" - 4" x 7"
        - Herford, Helen B: Wayland, MA, [no year] August 7, circa 1880s; cuid2069 (Box 61, Folder 20)
          Sent From: “Helen B. Herford”
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / History / Professional; "The Problem of the Northment / Letter to Judge Daly,” J. Toulmin Smith’s “The Discovery of America By The Norsemen”
        - Herzog, Wilhelm: Fußgönheim, Germany, 1887 December 29; cuid2070 (Box 61, Folder 21)
          Sent From: “Wilhelm Herzog”
        - Higginson, Henry Lee with Others: Boston, MA, 1878 January 7; 1890 June 21; cuid2071 (Box 61, Folder 22)
          Sent From: "H.L. [Henry Lee] Higginson"; "J.J. [James Jackson] Storrow, 40 State Street, Boston, [MA] / Washington, D.C."
          In Reference To: Business / Legal / Professional; Mr. James Russell; Patents
          Measurements: 5” x 6” - 5" x 8"
        - Higginson, JW: Cambridge, MA, 1890 April 27; cuid2072 (Box 61, Folder 23)
          Sent From: “J.W. Higginson”
        - Hill, Eliza Trask: Boston, MA, 1887 September 2; cuid2073 (Box 61, Folder 24)
          Sent From: “Secretary Mrs. Eliza Trask Hill, The New England Helping Hand Society, Box 1871, Boston, MA”
        - Hill, Ida F. Parker: Winchendon, MA, 1882 January 6; cuid2074 (Box 61, Folder 25)
          Sent From: “Ida F. Parker Hill”
          In Reference To: Academic / Education / Friendship / Personal / Social; Wellesley College
        - Hill, Julius W: Boston, MA, [no year] March 17, circa 1880s; cuid2075 (Box 61, Folder 26)
          Sent From: “Julius W. Hill, Adams House,” [Boston, MA]
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / History / Professional; “The Discovery of the Ancient City of Norumbega”
        - Hill, Thomas: Randolph, MA, 1885 August 29; cuid2076 (Box 61, Folder 27)
          Sent From: “Thomas Hill”
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / Native Americans / Professional / Travel; Indian Village near Mount Feake
        - Hilliard, George B: Boston, MA, 1890 May 15 & June 7; cuid2077 (Box 61, Folder 28)
          Sent From: “George B. Hilliard, J.W. Lewis & Company, Publishers, 244 Washington Street, Boston,” [MA], “United States Hotel, Boston,” [MA]
          In Reference To: Business / Professional; Dr. McKenzie; Mr. Lewis
        - Hills, E: Albany, NY, 1838 November 6; cuid2078 (Box 61, Folder 29)
          Addressed To: “E.N. [Eben Norton] Horsford, Esq., Moscow, Livingston County, NY"
          Sent From: “E. Hills”
          In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Social; Mr. Hall, Mrs. Hill & Harriet
        - Hind, SH: New York, NY, 1872 April 5; cuid2079 (Box 61, Folder 30)
          Sent From: “S.H. Hind”
          In Reference To: Business / Professional / Religion; Bishop Littlejohn, Episcopal Settlement
          1 Pages, Unbound
        - Hinman, George Wheeler: Oberlin, OH, 1889 December 16; cuid2080 (Box 61, Folder 31)
          Sent From: “George W. Hinman, Oberlin College, Oberlin, OH”
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / Professional; Charles River Valley, “Lost City [Norumbega] of New England”
          George Wheeler Hinman (November 19, 1864 - March 31, 1927) was an American educator, publisher, and writer. Hinman served as the president of Marietta College in Ohio from 1913 - 1918. Hinman’s library is preserved in the Marietta College Library in Marietta, OH.
        - Hinsdale, Harriet Hascall: Le Roy, NY, 1836 March 25; 1839 January 9 & July 18; cuid2081 (Box 61, Folder 32)
          3 Letters with Indentation, Notation, Postage & Seals
          Addressed To: “Dear Cousin Eben,” “Eben N. [Norton] Horsford, Albany, NY / Moscow, NY”
          Sent From: “H.H. / Harriet H. [Hascall] Hinsdale,” [Cousin of Eben Norton Horsford]
          In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Social; Eliza; Mr. Avery, Mr. Hale
        - Hinsen, Justin: Shelter Island, NY, 1887 August 25; cuid2082 (Box 61, Folder 33)
          Addressed To: “E.N. [Eben Norton] Horsford, Cambridge,” [MA]
          Sent From: “Justin Hinsen, Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island,” [NY]
        - Hitchcock, E: Amherst, MA, 1886 June 12; cuid2083 (Box 61, Folder 34)
          Sent From: “E. Hitchcock”
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / Financial / Professional; Mount Holyoke Seminary
        - Hjorth, F: Cambridgeport, MA, 1887 March 7; 1889 September 24; cuid2084 (Box 61, Folder 35)
          Sent From: “F. Hjorth, Dealer & Importer Of Norwegian Goods / Importer, Commission Merchant, Dealer in Scandinavian Produce, 404 & 406 Main Street, Cambridgeport, MA”
          Measurements: 5.75” x 8.75” - 8” x 10”
        - Hodges, NDC: New York, NY, 1887 June 28; cuid2085 (Box 61, Folder 36)
          Sent From: “N.D.C. Hodges, Editor’s Office, The Swiss Cross, 47 Lafayette Place, New York,” [NY]
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / Professional; Volapük
        - Hogins, HH: Shelter Island Heights, NY, 1886 August 14; cuid2086 (Box 61, Folder 37)
          Sent From: “H.H. Hogins, D.P. Hathaway, Prospect House, Shelter Island Heights, Suffolk County, New York / 549 West 75th Street, New York,” [NY]
          In Reference To: Business / Professional / Social; Shelter Island Yacht Club
        - Holcomb, Amasa: Southwick, MA, 1844 June 28; cuid2087 (Box 61, Folder 38)
          Sent From: “Amasa Holcomb”
          In Reference To: Business / Professional / Science / Technology
          Amasa Holcomb (1787 - 1875) was an American businessman, civil engineer, farmer, surveyor, and manufacturer of surveying instruments and telescopes. Holcomb archival material can be found in the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library at Yale University in New Haven, CT and the Smithsonian Institute in Washington, D.C.
        - Holmes, Oliver Wendell: Beverly Farms & Boston, MA, 1879 July 31; 1886 January 31; cuid2088 (Box 61, Folder 39)
          Addressed To: “Miss Dering”; “Professor [Eben Norton] Horsford”
          Sent From: “O.W. / Oliver Wendell Holmes”
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / Professional / Social; "The Problem of the Northmen / Letter to Judge Daly," Norumbega, John Cabot’s Landfall in 1497
          Measurements: 4.75” x 6” - 4.5” x 7”
          Oliver Wendell Holmes, Sr. (August 29, 1809 – October 7, 1894) was an American author, lecturer, medical reformer, physician, poet, and professor. Based in Boston, MA, Holmes was a member of the Fireside Poets. The Book & Print Collection of the Holmes Family, also known as the Oliver Wendell Holmes Library, is preserved at the Library of Congress in Washington, D.C. In addition, Holmes correspondence is available online through Lehigh University's “I Remain: A Digital Archive of Letters, Manuscripts, and Ephemera.”
        - Hooker, Henrietta E: South Hadley, MA, [no year] May 4, circa 1880s; cuid2089 (Box 61, Folder 40)
          Sent From: “Henrietta E. Hooker, Mount Holyoke Seminary, South Hadley, MA”
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / Financial / Professional / Social; Botany, Zoology, Physiology, Dr. Asa Gray, Cambridge Botanical Gardens, “Mary Lyon Fund”
        - Hooper, Mrs. J: Washington, D.C., [no year] January 27, circa 1880s; cuid2090 (Box 61, Folder 41)
          Addressed To: “Professor [Eben Norton] & Miss Horsford, Smithsonian [Institute],” [Washington, D.C.]
          Sent From: “Mrs. J. / S. Hooper, 334 H. Street,” [Washington, D.C.]
          In Reference To: Friendship / Personal / Social; Mr. & Mrs. [Elizabeth Cabot] Agassiz
          Measurements: 4.75” x 3” - 4.5” x 5.75”
        - Hopkins, George G: Brooklyn, NY, 1890 August 18; cuid2091 (Box 61, Folder 42)
          Sent From: “George G. Hopkins, M.D., 350 Washington Avenue, Brooklyn, NY”
          In Reference To: Friendship / Personal / Social / Travel; Visiting Shelter Island
        - Hopkins, William K: Brockport, Canandaigua & Geneva, NY, 1836 September 30 - 1837 June 1; cuid2092 (Box 61, Folder 43)
          Addressed To: “Mr. Eben [Norton] Horsford, New York Engineers, Moscow,” [Livingston County, NY], “Party of William K. Hopkins”
          Sent From: “William K. Hopkins, Brockport / Canandaigua / Geneva, NY”
          Measurements: 3.5” x 2.75” - 7.75” x 12.75”
        - Hopkins, Woolsey R: New York, NY; Shippan Point, CT, 1885 December 25; 1886 July 18 - 1887 December 19; 1889 February 20 & August 9; cuid2093 (Box 61, Folder 44)
          10 Letters with Indentation
          Addressed To: “My Dear Friend & Cousin,” “Professor E.N. [Eben Norton] Horsford”
          Sent From: “Woolsey R. Hopkins, 8 West 51st Street / 160 West 59th Street / The Langham, 52 South Fifth Avenue,” [New York, NY],” “Holiday House, Shippan Point, Stamford,” [CT]
          38 Pages, Bound & Unbound
        - Horne, PH: New York, NY, [no year] November 23, circa 1840s; cuid2094 (Box 61, Folder 45)
          Sent From: [C.H. / P.H. Horne], “180 Fulton Street, New York,” [NY]
        - Horsford, Ambrose: Moira, NY, 1834 March 4; cuid2095 (Box 61, Folder 46)
          Addressed To: “Mr. Eben [Norton] Horsford, Moscow, Livingston County, NY”
          Sent From: “Ambrose Horsford”
          In Reference To: Family / Genealogy / Professional
        - Horsford, Cornelia Conway Felton (Nellie): Cambridge, MA, 1889 July 27; [no year] July 27, undated, circa 1860s - 1880s; cuid2096 (Box 61, Folder 47)
          4 Letters, 3 Envelopes with Notation
          Addressed To: “My dear Papa,” [Eben Norton Horsford]
          Sent From: “Nellie Horsford, Craigie Street,” [Cambridge, MA], [Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford, Daughter of Eben Norton Horsford]
          Measurements: 2.75” x 1.75” - 5” x 8”
        - Horsford, Elise: Rochester, NY, 1843 July 29 & September 9; 1844 May 17; cuid2097 (Box 61, Folder 48)
          Addressed To: “My dear Brother,” “Professor E.N. [Eben Norton] Horsford, Albany,” [NY]
          Sent From: “Elise [Norton Horsford],” [Sister of Eben Norton Horsford]
        - Horsford, Eliza Norton: Auburn, Le Roy & Moscow, NY, 1835 January 31 - 1839 January 12; cuid2098 (Box 61, Folder 49)
          Addressed To: “My dear Brother,” “Mr. Eben N. [Norton] Horsford, Albany,” [NY], “Assistant State Geologist, Elmira / Jefferson, Chemung County,” [NY], “℅ Mr. Edwards, Moscow, Livingston County,” [NY], “℅ William R. Hopkins, Esq., Dunkirk, Chautauqua County, NY,” “Le Roy, Genesee County,” [NY], “Troy, NY”
          Sent From: “Eliza N.H. [Norton Horsford], Harmony Retreat, Auburn, NY,” “Le Roy Female Seminary,” [Le Roy, NY], “Moscow,” [NY], [Sister of Eben Norton Horsford]
          Measurements: 3.25” x 2.25” - 8” x 12.75”
        - Horsford, Eliza Norton: Elmira & Moscow, NY, 1839 January 27 - 1841 January 22; cuid2099 (Box 61, Folder 50)
          12 Letters with Indentation, Notation & Postage
          Addressed To: "My dear Brother Eben,” “Mr. / Professor Eben N. [Norton] Horsford, ℅ Mr. Reddington, No. 32 Commercial Building, South Market Street, Albany / Rochester,” [NY]
          Sent From: “E. / Eliza N.H. [Norton Horsford], Elmira / Locust Lodge / Moscow Academy, Moscow, NY,” [Sister of Eben Norton Horsford]
          44 Pages, Bound & Unbound
          Measurements: 7.75” x 9.75” - 7.75” x 12.5”
        - Horsford, Eliza Norton: Le Roy, Moscow & Rochester, NY, 1841 April 25 - 1843 March 25; cuid2100 (Box 61, Folder 51)
          Addressed To: “My dear Brother,” “Mr. Eben N. [Norton] Horsford, ℅ Dr. Seymour / Miss Bissell / Mr. & Mrs. A.P. Hascall / Mr. Mason / Mr. Parsons / Mr. Patterson / No. 26 or 68 North Pearl Street, Albany / Jefferson, Chemung County,” [NY]”
          Sent From: “Eliza N. [Norton Horsford], Le Roy Female Academy, Le Roy / Moscow, NY,” “Packet Boat, Rochester,” [NY], [Sister of Eben Norton Horsford]
          64 Pages, Bound & Unbound
          Measurements: 4.75” x 7.25” - 7.75” x 12.5”
        - Horsford, Eliza Norton: Moscow, NY, 1843 July 16 - 1844 April 19; [no year] May 15 & December 23, circa 1840s; cuid2101 (Box 61, Folder 52)
          Addressed To: “Professor E.N. [Eben Norton] Horsford, ℅ Dr. Bissell / Dr. Seymour, Albany,” [NY]
          Sent From: “Eliza [Norton Horsford],” “Island Home,” “Moscow,” [NY], [Sister of Eben Norton Horsford]
          31 Pages, Bound & Unbound
          Measurements: 3.5” x 3.5” - 8” x 12.75”
        - Horsford, Eliza Norton & Maria Charity: Moscow, NY, 1837 August 21 - 1840 September 26; 1844 January 25; 1873 June 29; cuid2102 (Box 61, Folder 53)
          Addressed To: “My dearest Brother / My dear Son,” “Mr. Eben N. [Norton] Horsford, Albany,” [NY], “Newark, New Castle County, DE,” “Rensselaer Institute, Troy, NY”; “Miss Julia Horsford, ℅ E.N. Horsford, Esq., No. 30 Jay Street, Albany,” [NY]; “My dearest Sister Eliza [Norton Horsford],” [To Unidentified Location, Possibly Moscow, NY]
          Sent From: “Eben [Norton Horsford]"; “Sister E. / Eliza N. [Norton Horsford], Moscow, NY," [Sister of Eben Norton Horsford]; “M.C. [Maria Charity] Horsford,” [Mother of Eben Norton Horsford]
          Measurements: 5.75” x 9” - 8” x 13”
        - Horsford, FJ: New York, NY, 1842 September 28; cuid2103 (Box 61, Folder 54)
          Addressed To: "E.N. [Eben Norton] Horsford, Esq., Albany, NY"
          Sent From: "F.J. Horsford, 34 Wall Street," [New York, NY]
          Measurements: 8" x 10"
        - Horsford, FS: Eider River, Germany, 1885 May 6; cuid2104 (Box 61, Folder 55)
          Sent From: “F.S.H. / F.S. Horsford, The Eider,” [Germany], [Cousin of Eben Norton Horsford]
        - Horsford D.D., J: Trinidad, 1887 March 18; 1889 July 17; cuid2105 (Box 61, Folder 56)
          Addressed To: “Professor [Eben Norton] Horsford, Cambridge,” [MA]
          Sent From: “J. Horsford, D.D.”
        - [Horsford], James: Hartford, CT, 1877 August 2; 1886 February 21; 1887 July 10; 1888 December 26; cuid2106 (Box 61, Folder 57)
          Addressed To: “My dear Brother,” [Eben Norton Horsford]
          Sent From: “James, 991 Asylum Avenue, Hartford, CT,” [Possibly Horsford / Stone]
          In Reference To: Academic / Education / Family / Financial / Friendship / History / Personal / Social / Travel; "John Cabot's Landfall"; Julia Horsford; Wellesley College
        - Horsford, Jerediah: Albany & Moscow, NY, 1831 February 4 - 1841 April 27; cuid2107 (Box 61, Folder 58)
          Addressed To: “Eben, Eliza, & Julia,” “Master / Mr. E.N. [Eben Norton] Horsford, Assistant State Geologist, Ellicottville, Cattaraugus County, NY,” “Moscow, Livingston County,” [NY], “No. 30 Jay Street, Albany, NY,” “Of the Geological Corps, Elmira, Tioga County, NY,” “Student High School, Genesee,” [NY], “Troy, NY”
          Sent From: “J. [Jerediah] Horsford, Albany / Moscow,” [NY], [Father of Eben Norton Horsford]
        - Horsford, Jerediah: Moscow, NY, 1841 October 24 - 1844 April 20; [no year] June 27 - November 2, circa 1840 - 1859; cuid2108 (Box 61, Folder 59)
          10 Letters with Indentation, Notation & Postage, 1 American Telegraph Envelope with Printed Message
          Addressed To: “E.N. [Eben Norton] Horsford, Albany,” [NY], “Cambridge, MA,” “Geneseo, NY”; “Mr. Jerediah Horsford, Moscow, Livingston County,” [NY]
          Sent From: “Eliza [Horsford], Auburn, NY,”; “J. [Jerediah], Horsford, Moscow,” [NY], [Father & Sister of Eben Norton Horsford]
          In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Social / Travel; Notification of Mrs. [Maria Charity] Horsford’s Death
          Measurements: 0.5” x 20” - 7.75” x 12.5”
        - Horsford, Jerediah & Maria Charity: Moscow, NY, 1840 October 18; [no year] January 25, circa 1840 - 1850s; cuid2109 (Box 61, Folder 60)
          2 Letters with Notation & Postage, 1 Hand Drawn Map
          Addressed To: “Mr. E.N. [Eben Norton] Horsford, Albany,” [NY]; “My dear Father & Mother,” “J. Horford, Esq., Moscow, Livingston County, NY”
          Sent From: “E.N. Horsford”; “J.H. [Jerediah Horsford], M.C.H. [Maria Charity Horsford],” [Parents of Eben Norton Horsford]
          In Reference To: Business / Family / Friendship / Personal / Professional / Science / Social / Travel; 1 Ink Illustration of Genesee Valley Canal, Fossil Coalities about Moscow, NY, Dr. Emmons, the Geologist of the 2nd District
          Measurements: 7.25” x 5.5” - 7.25” x 9.75”
        - Horsford, Jerediah & NA Norton: Newark, DE, 1843 August 31; cuid2110 (Box 61, Folder 61)